clarins.com.au 2018-04-06

# eCommerce Solutions On-Demand | Demandware Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to Trimex Pty Ltd* **("Clarins", "we", "us", "our")** and its affiliates and explains how we handle personal information and comply with the requirements of applicable Australian privacy laws ( **Privacy Laws** ). If you have further questions relating to this Privacy Policy, please contact CustomerCare.AU@Clarins.com.

_*Trimex Pty Ltd is a wholly owned subsidiary of the Clarins Group of Companies._

We recognise the importance of your privacy, and that you have a right to know how your personal information is collected and used.

#### 1\. Collection of personal information

1.1 We collect personal information from you when you subscribe to our emails, or otherwise provide your details to us, for the purposes set out in section 2.2 below.

1.2 We usually collect personal information through: 

(a) our websites;

(b) orders for products or services;

(c) requests for brochures, to join a mailing list or to be contacted for further information about our products or services, either online or in hard copy, e.g. through our Customer Registry Card;

(d) provision of customer service and support;

(e) responses to surveys or research conducted by us or on our behalf; and

(f) entries into competitions or trade promotions conducted by us or on our behalf.

1.3 If you do not provide us with the information we request, we may not be able to fulfil the applicable purposes of collection, such as to supply our customer services to you.

1.4 Where practicable, we will collect personal information directly from you. If we receive information about you from someone else (for example from someone who supplies goods or services to us), we will take reasonable steps to ensure you are aware that we have collected personal information about you and the circumstances of the collection.

1.5 The types of personal information Clarins will collect from you will depend on the circumstances in which that information is collected. It may include: 

(a) contact details (i.e. your name, address, email and phone details);

(b) information about your previous interactions with Clarins, including prior purchases;

(c) information required for you to do business with us including bank account details and any other relevant financial information;

(d) age and information on personal lifestyle preferences; and

(e) statistical information regarding the use of Clarins websites, including website users' IP addresses and the dates and times of visits.

#### 2\. Use and disclosure of personal information

2.1 We will only use and disclose your personal information in accordance with Privacy Laws and this Privacy Policy.

2.2 Our main purposes for collecting, holding, using and disclosing personal information are: 

(a) to supply products or services to our customers, including providing information about our products or services;

(b) to respond to enquiries from existing or prospective customers seeking information about our products or services;

(c) to provide customer support; and

(d) to undertake research, surveys and analyse statistical information.

2.3 We generally explain at the time we collect personal information how we will use or disclose that information. We will only use or disclose personal information for a purpose other than that for which it was collected or a related purpose if you have consented to the different use or disclosure or the use or disclosure is otherwise allowed by the Privacy Laws.

2.4 In carrying out our business, it may be necessary to share information about you with organisations that provide services to us. We would not otherwise routinely disclose personal information to another organisation unless: 

(a) required by law; 

(b) we believe it necessary to provide you with a service which you have requested;

(c) the assets and operations of our business are transferred to another party as a going concern;

(d) it is necessary to protect the rights, property or personal safety of any of our customers, any member of the public or our interests; or

(e) you have provided your consent.

_Service providers_

2.5 In order to maximise the quality and efficiency of our services and our business operations, we may in the future use third party service providers, who may sometimes have access to personal information held by us and may use it on our behalf. We require our service providers to adhere to strict privacy guidelines and not to keep this information or use it for any unauthorised purposes.

_Disclosure of information outside the jurisdiction of collection_

2.6 We do not generally disclose personal information outside Australia. In the conduct of our business, we may hold your personal information on servers located in various countries, including France and Hong Kong. The privacy laws of those countries may not provide the same level of protection as the privacy laws of the country from which the personal information was collected. However, this does not change our commitment to safeguard your privacy and we will comply with all applicable laws relating to the cross-border disclosure of data.

_Direct marketing_

2.7 We may, from time to time, send marketing materials to current or prospective customers, in accordance with applicable laws or with your prior consent.

2.8 If you are receiving promotional information from us and do not wish to receive this information any longer, please contact us directly on CustomerCare.AU@Clarins.com and ask to be removed from our mailing lists, or use the unsubscribe facilities included in our marketing communications.

_Our website privacy practices_

2.9 We sometimes use cookie technology on our websites to provide information and services to website visitors. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record keeping purposes and are a necessary part of facilitating online transactions. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. Cookies are useful to estimate our number of customers and determine overall traffic patterns through our websites.

2.10 If you do not wish to receive any cookies you may set your browser to refuse cookies. This may mean you will not be able to take full advantage of the services on the website.

#### 3\. Links to other websites

3.1 Our websites may contain links to third party websites. These linked sites are not under our control and we are not responsible for the content of those sites nor are those sites subject to our Privacy Policy. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website we recommend that you examine the terms and conditions and Privacy Policy of the relevant site. Clarins is not responsible for any practices on linked websites that might breach your privacy.

#### 4\. Accessing, modifying or deleting your personal information

4.1 If at any time you want to know exactly what personal information we hold about you, you are welcome to request access to your record by contacting us at CustomerCare.AU@Clarins.com. Our file of your information will usually be made available to you within 14 days.

4.2 If at any time you wish to change personal information that we hold about you because it is inaccurate or out of date, please contact us at CustomerCare.AU@Clarins.com and we will amend this record. If you wish to have your personal information deleted, please let us know in the same manner as referred to above and we will take all reasonable steps to delete it unless we need to keep it for legal reasons.

#### 5\. Storage and security of personal information

5.1 We will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information which we hold about you, and to keep this information accurate, up to date and complete. Your information is stored in electronic and physical records maintained by Clarins. We require our employees and data processors to respect the confidentiality or any personal information held by us.

5.2 The transmission of data via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website, and any transmission is at your own risk.

5.3 When we no longer need to use your information, we will take steps to properly de-identify or destroy it.

#### 6\. Contacting us

6.1 If you have any concerns or complaints about how we handle your personal information, or if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: CustomerCare.AU@Clarins.com.

6.2 In most cases we will ask that you put your request in writing to us. We will investigate your complaint and will use reasonable endeavours to respond to you in writing within 30 days of receiving the written complaint. If we fail to respond to your complaint within 30 days of receiving it in writing or if you are dissatisfied with the response that you receive from us, you may have the right, depending on the jurisdiction, to make a complaint to the Australian privacy regulatory authority, the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner. Current contact details for the OAIC are available on the OAIC's website at www.oaic.gov.au.

#### 7\. Future changes

7.1 We may change this Privacy Policy at any time and we will notify you by posting an updated version of the policy on our website. If at any point we decide to use personal information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected we will notify users by email or via a prominent notice on our website, and where necessary we will seek the prior consent of our users.
